Sometimes, we can feel like staying away or getting angry even when what makes us feel
that way isn't right near us.
For example, Mike might want to stay away in gym class when Mr. Ramos is there, but
he might also want to stay away when he sees someone from gym class and thinks about Mr.
Ramos.
We call these reminders triggers.
We want to show you how triggers work.
And the picture above is Dave.
Dave is usually an easygoing kid who gets along with everyone.
But recently, Dave's grandfather, who helped raise him, died.
Since then, Dave doesn't want to talk much with his friends.
He likes to stay in his room.
He misses watching old Simpson shows with his grandfather playing cards and talking
about his day.
When his mom makes him come out of his room, he gets angry and they often argue when he
has to go to school or eat dinner.
He just wants to be left alone.
Even when he's in his room, he feels sad most of the time.
Now answer some true or false questions about Dave.